<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muses - Digital Musical Instruments on Muses</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Muses - Digital Musical Instruments on Muses</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 13:29:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notions of Time</title>
      <link>/not_src/not/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 08:16:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/not_src/not/</guid>
      <description> Overview More Information Tools and documentation for the current implementation of notions of time:
 Haskell source code.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVG Interfaces</title>
      <link>/svg_interfaces_src/svg_interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 08:16:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/svg_interfaces_src/svg_interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Overview SVG Interfaces is an on going project exploring the design and implementation of custom controller interfaces, bridging the issue of user mapping between action and sound in interactive music systems. We have developed a simple framework utilizing functional specifications for musical interfaces and their mappings. The system is based on a subset of Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG); interfaces are described using a simple Haskell based &amp;lsquo;controller DSL&amp;rsquo; or equally using a vector drawing application (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>research papers</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 15:07:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>Benedict R. Gaster, Nathan Renney and Carinna Parraman. (2019) Fun with Interfaces (SVG Interfaces for Musical Expression). Submitted for publication.
Renney, H., Gaster, B. R. and Mitchell, T. (2019) OpenCL vs: Accelerated finite-difference digital synthesis. In: IWOCL&amp;rsquo;19 - 7th International Workshop on OpenCL, NorthEastern University Boston, USA, 12-14 May, 2019.
Gaster, B. R., Renney, N. and Mitchell, T. (2018) Outside the block syndicate: Translating Faust&amp;rsquo;s algebra of blocks to the arrows framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 13:29:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Muses is under active development by Benedict R. Gaster and Nathan Renney, along with contrabutions from Carinna Parraman and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muses - Digital Musical Instruments</title>
      <link>/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 13:29:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>Muses is an umbrella project for work being done in the Physical Computing Group at University of West of England (UWE). Our particular focus is applying programming language theory and practice, physical computing, networking, and musicial theory to design and implementation of Digitial Musical Instruments (DMI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 13:29:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>SVG Interfaces SVG Interfaces is an on going project exploring the design and implementation of custom controller interfaces, bridging the issue of user mapping between action and sound in interactive music systems.
More information can be found here.
Notions of Time Music provides a means to explore time by sequencing musical events in a seemingly endless and expressive way. This potential seems to far exceed the ability of digital systems to enable composers and performers to fully explore musical time due to the influence of Western musical traditions on implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>