<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pats on Muses</title>
    <link>/pat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pats on Muses</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:42:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/pat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>/pat/listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:42:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pat/listen/</guid>
      <description>Audio Examples Perhaps the best way to get familiar with Pat is to take a listen.
We can listen to an example of Pat directly converted to audio in this example:
To help get a feel for what is happening, we can listen to this pattern looped, with some percussion used to ground where the sequence synchronizes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>/pat/synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:42:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pat/synth/</guid>
      <description>Muses Audio Platform We expose a method for configuring the step sequencer found in the Muses Audio Platform using Pat.
In this screen grab of the application, we can see the following pat expression has been used to layout the step sequencer:
y y y y r y | : | r y y y | : | r y y y o y o</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pat</title>
      <link>/pat/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 08:16:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pat/overview/</guid>
      <description>Overview Pat is a miniature domain specific programming language (DSL) which is heavily influenced by Tidal Cycles. This language was implemented as a means to explore an abstract representation of sequences of musical events for digital musical instruments.
We have used Pat to illustrate a number of perspectives on this and will continue to use it in future work.
Applications - Audio Examples We can listen to an example of Pat directly converted to audio in here and get an idea of how Pat is used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>